<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>System Editor on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/system-editor/</link><description>Recent content in System Editor on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/system-editor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigation Tree</title><link>/gui-reference/system-editor/navigation-tree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/system-editor/navigation-tree/</guid><description>The navigation tree is shown in the left panel of the system editor. It is used for accessing the various components of a system description. A node in the tree can be double clicked to view (or hide) the sub tree of the node.
The root of the navigation tree is named Project if the system is unnamed, otherwise the name of the system (i.e. the name of the XML-file).</description></item><item><title>Drawing</title><link>/gui-reference/system-editor/drawing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/system-editor/drawing/</guid><description>The rightmost panel of the system editor is used for drawing automata. There are currently four drawing tools named Select, Location, Edge, and Nail represented by the buttons in the tool bar.
Select tool: The select tool is used to select, move, modify and delete elements. Elements can be selected by clicking on them or by dragging a rubber band arround one or more elements. Elements can be added or removed from a selection by holding down the control key while clicking on the element.</description></item><item><title>Declarations</title><link>/gui-reference/system-editor/declarations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/system-editor/declarations/</guid><description>Types, constants, variables and functions can be defined in the global scope by placing them in the global section labelled Declarations or System declarations, or locally for a template by placing in the Declarations section of a template.
Processes are instantiated by placing a process assignments in the System declarations section.
Finally, the system is defined as a parallel composition of a number of processes by placing a system declaration in the System declarations section.</description></item></channel></rss>