<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>System Definition on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/</link><description>Recent content in System Definition on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Template Instantiation</title><link>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/template-instantiation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/template-instantiation/</guid><description>New templates can be defined from existing templates using the grammar for Instantiation. The new template has the same automaton structure and the same local variables as the template it is defined from. However, arguments are provided for any formal parameters of the template, thus changing the interface of the template.
Instantiation ::= ID [ &amp;#39;(&amp;#39; [Parameters] &amp;#39;)&amp;#39; ] &amp;#39;=&amp;#39; ID &amp;#39;(&amp;#39; [Arguments] &amp;#39;)&amp;#39; &amp;#39;;&amp;#39; Template instantiation is most often used to bind formal parameters to actual arguments.</description></item><item><title>Progress Measures</title><link>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/progress-measures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/progress-measures/</guid><description>A progress measure is an expression that defines progress in the model. It should be weakly monotonically increasing, although occasional decreasses are acceptable. E.g. sequence numbers used in communication protocols might be used to define a progress measure, provided that the sequence number does not overflow to often.
If progress measures are defined, UPPAAL uses the generalized sweepline method to reduce the memory usage. However to be efficient, the domain of a progress measure should not be too large - otherwise performance might degrade significantly.</description></item><item><title>Gantt Chart</title><link>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/gantt-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/gantt-chart/</guid><description>A Gantt chart, commonly used in project management, is a bar chart that shows activities displayed against time. On the left of the chart is a list of the activities and along the top is a suitable time scale. Each activity is represented by a bar; the position and length of the bar reflect the start date, duration and end date of the activity.
In UPPAAL Gantt Charts are used to automatic visualize traces in Concrete Simulator.</description></item></channel></rss>