<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Templates on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/</link><description>Recent content in Templates on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Locations</title><link>https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/locations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/locations/</guid><description>Locations of a timed automaton are graphically represented as circles. If a timed automaton is considered as a directed graph, then locations represent the vertices of this graph. Locations are connected by edges.
Names Locations can have an optional name. Besides serving as an identifier allowing you to refer to the location from the requirement specification language, named locations are useful when documenting the model. The name must be a valid identifier and location names share the name space with variables, types, templates, etc.</description></item><item><title>Edges</title><link>https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/edges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uppaalmodelchecker.github.io/docs.uppaal.org/language-reference/system-description/templates/edges/</guid><description>Locations are connected by edges. Edges are annotated with selections, guards, synchronisations and updates. Edges may also have branches of possible destinations with their own updates and probabilistic weights.
Selections Selections non-deterministically bind a given identifier to a value in a given range. The other three labels of an edge are within the scope of this binding. Guards An edge is enabled in a state if and only if the guard evaluates to true.</description></item></channel></rss>