<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Menu Bar on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/</link><description>Recent content in Menu Bar on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/menu-bar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>File Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/file/</guid><description>&lt;p>The leftmost menu of the menu bar is the file menu. It is mainly used to open and save (part of) system descriptions or requirement specifications created in UPPAAL. The available items are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New System:&lt;/strong> re-initiates the editor with an empty system.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Open System:&lt;/strong> loads an existing system from file. The corresponding requirement specification (i.e. same file name but with the suffix .q) is loaded into the verifier, if it exists.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Save System:&lt;/strong> saves the system in the editor to file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Save System As:&lt;/strong> saves the system in the editor to a specified file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Import Template:&lt;/strong> imports template(s) from an existing system description. A dialog window is shown which allows a subset of the available templates to be imported.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Export Template:&lt;/strong> exports the currently edited template in Encapsulated Postscript format to file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New Queries:&lt;/strong> re-initiates the requirement specification editor with an empty file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Open Queries:&lt;/strong> loads an existing set of requirement specifications from file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Save Queries:&lt;/strong> saves the requirement specifications in the editor to file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Save Queries As:&lt;/strong> saves the requirement specifications in the editor to a specified file name.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Exit:&lt;/strong> exits UPPAAL.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Edit Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/edit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/edit/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Edit menu offers a set of commands supported in the system editor. The items are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Undo:&lt;/strong> reverses the most recent editing action. This function is only available in the editor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Redo:&lt;/strong> re-applies the editing action that has most recently been reversed by the Undo action. This function is only available in the editor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cut:&lt;/strong> removes the selected text and places it in the clipboard. There must be an active text selection.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Copy:&lt;/strong> places a copy of the selected text in the clipboard. There must be an active text selection.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Paste:&lt;/strong> places text in the clipboard at the cursor location in the currently active editor. There must be text in the clipboard, and an editor must be active.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Delete:&lt;/strong> delete selected text. There must be an active text selection.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Insert Template:&lt;/strong> adds a new empty template to the system description.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Remove Template:&lt;/strong> removes the currently selected template from the system description. There must be a template selected.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>View Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/view/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/view/</guid><description>&lt;p>The view menu is used to modify the appearance of the system currently shown in the &lt;a href="/gui-reference/system-editor/">system editor&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/">simulator&lt;/a>. The items are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Zoom:&lt;/strong> shows a sub menu with fixed zoom values, zoom to fit, and itemes for zooming in, out, or to normal size. A change in the zoom value affects the templates the editor or the processes in the simulator (if one of the tools is active).&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Labels:&lt;/strong> shows a sub menu from which one can select which type of labels should be shown in the drawing area. Even when hidden, all labels can be seen in the tooltip of locations and edges.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tools Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/tools/</guid><description>&lt;p>The tools menu contains a set of tools useful in the &lt;a href="/gui-reference/system-editor/">system edtior&lt;/a>. The items are:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Check Syntax:&lt;/strong> checks if syntax and types are correct in the edited system. Any found errors and warnings are listed in the lower part of the &lt;a href="/gui-reference/system-editor/drawing/">drawing area&lt;/a> of the system editor, and (when applicable) underlinded in the automata.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Convert Syntax:&lt;/strong> assists in convering a system complying with the syntax used in UPPAAL 3.4 to the current syntax.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Align to Grid:&lt;/strong> makes all existing objects of the current template align to the specified drawing grid.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Plot Composer:&lt;/strong> creates a new &lt;a href="../Verifier/PlotComposer.html">Plot Composer&lt;/a> window to superimpose multiple results from statistical model checking in the &lt;a href="/gui-reference/verifier/">Verifier&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Options Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/options/</guid><description>&lt;p>The options menu contains settings to control the behavior of the model-checker.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="search-order">Search Order&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This option influences the order in which the state space is explored.&lt;/p>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Breadth first&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Search the state space in breadth first search order. This is typically the most efficient option when the complete state space must be searched. When generating shortest or fastest traces, this is likely the best setting.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Depth first&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Search the state space in depth first search order. If a counter example or witnessing trace is expected to exist, this setting is usually better than the breadth first setting. It is not recommended to use this search order when generating shortest or fastest traces.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Random depth first&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Search the state space in randomised depth first search order. If a counter example or witnessing trace is expected to exist, this is usually the best setting. Due to the randomisation, traces may vary from run to run. It is not recommended to use this search order when generating shortest or fastest traces.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl>
&lt;h2 id="state-space-reduction">State Space Reduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When searching the state space, UPPAAL does not necessarily have to store all states in memory in order to guarantee termination. This option influences how aggressively UPPAAL tries to avoid storing states. There is normally a tradeoff between space and speed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Help Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/help/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;strong>help&lt;/strong> menu has two items: Help which opens a separate window showing the help pages, and &lt;strong>About&lt;/strong> which opens a window showing the version number and information about the copyrights of UPPAAL.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>