<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Menu Bar on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/</link><description>Recent content in Menu Bar on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/menu-bar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>File Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/file/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/file/</guid><description>The leftmost menu of the menu bar is the file menu. It is mainly used to open and save (part of) system descriptions or requirement specifications created in UPPAAL. The available items are:
New System: re-initiates the editor with an empty system. Open System: loads an existing system from file. The corresponding requirement specification (i.e. same file name but with the suffix .q) is loaded into the verifier, if it exists.</description></item><item><title>Edit Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/edit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/edit/</guid><description>The Edit menu offers a set of commands supported in the system editor. The items are:
Undo: reverses the most recent editing action. This function is only available in the editor. Redo: re-applies the editing action that has most recently been reversed by the Undo action. This function is only available in the editor. Cut: removes the selected text and places it in the clipboard. There must be an active text selection.</description></item><item><title>View Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/view/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/view/</guid><description>The view menu is used to modify the appearance of the system currently shown in the system editor and the simulator. The items are:
Zoom: shows a sub menu with fixed zoom values, zoom to fit, and itemes for zooming in, out, or to normal size. A change in the zoom value affects the templates the editor or the processes in the simulator (if one of the tools is active).</description></item><item><title>Tools Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/tools/</guid><description>The tools menu contains a set of tools useful in the system edtior. The items are:
Check Syntax: checks if syntax and types are correct in the edited system. Any found errors and warnings are listed in the lower part of the drawing area of the system editor, and (when applicable) underlinded in the automata. Convert Syntax: assists in convering a system complying with the syntax used in UPPAAL 3.4 to the current syntax.</description></item><item><title>Options Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/options/</guid><description>The options menu contains settings to control the behavior of the model-checker.
Search Order This option influences the order in which the state space is explored.
Breadth first Search the state space in breadth first search order. This is typically the most efficient option when the complete state space must be searched. When generating shortest or fastest traces, this is likely the best setting. Depth first Search the state space in depth first search order.</description></item><item><title>Help Menu</title><link>/gui-reference/menu-bar/help/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/menu-bar/help/</guid><description>The help menu has two items: Help which opens a separate window showing the help pages, and About which opens a window showing the version number and information about the copyrights of UPPAAL.</description></item></channel></rss>