<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Verifier on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/verifier/</link><description>Recent content in Verifier on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/verifier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Specifying Requirements</title><link>/gui-reference/verifier/specifying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/verifier/specifying/</guid><description>&lt;p>An overview of the system requirements (called queries below and in the GUI) is shown in the panel named &lt;em>Overview&lt;/em> of the verifier. The toggle button &lt;em>Comments/Queries&lt;/em> is used to control if the queries or the comments are to be shown in the overview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Queries are selected and de-selected using the mouse alone, or in combination with the Shift or the Control key of the keyboard (use the Shift key to (de-)select a range of entries and the Control key to (de-)select single entries). The first selected requirement and its comment is always shown in the two editor fields named &lt;em>Query&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Comment&lt;/em>, where they may be edited.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verifying Requirements</title><link>/gui-reference/verifier/verifying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/verifier/verifying/</guid><description>&lt;p>The queries (i.e. the system requirements) are verified from the verifier interface of UPPAAL. A verification is always performed according to the settings specified in the &lt;a href="/gui-reference/menu-bar/options/">Options menu&lt;/a> of the main menu bar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The selected queries are verified when the button named &lt;em>Check&lt;/em> is pressed. The verification progress dialog displays the progress of how many queries have been verified, what is the current load of a passed-waiting list, current processor time usage (the time spent for verification is in blue, the time spent by operating system is in red), current usage of host&amp;rsquo;s random access memory (verification memory is in blue, memory used by other running processes is in gray and operating system cache and buffers are in yellow), swap disk usage (swapped out verification is in blue, other is in grey). Note that resource figures do not include the overhead of UPPAAL GUI and command line utilities (like &lt;tt>memtime&lt;/tt> run on &lt;tt>verifyta&lt;/tt>) are more accurate. Some figures are not available on some OSes (system cache allocation is not documented on Windows API and swap usage per process is not maintained by Linux kernel), therefore they might not show up.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>