<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Concrete Simulator on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/</link><description>Recent content in Concrete Simulator on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simulation Control</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/simulation-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/simulation-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>The simulation control is the left panel of the simulator. It is used to control the simulation and to select the state or transition to be visualized in the others panels of the simulator. The control panel is divided in two parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The upper part is used for performing step-by-step simulation. The &lt;em>Transition chooser&lt;/em> area is a clickable area where vertical axis displays the active transitions at this location and horizontal axis displays the time at which the transition will be ï¬red. The time interval where a transition is enabled and the time interval where a transition is selectable are colored in different way. The time interval in which a transition can be fired (where the transition is selectable) is delimited by markers: one small circle at the beginning and one at the end of the interval (full if it is close, empty if it is open). When the mouse move to a selectable area, the color of the interval become brighter. By clicking one can select a specific transition and a specific time for firing the transition. The selected transition will be highlighted. The time selected is displayed in the &lt;em>Delay&lt;/em>-combo box. One can also specified directly the time in the &lt;em>Delay&lt;/em>-combo, once the transition has been selected. If one click in a non-selectable zone of a transition, the tool chooses the closest valid time. The &lt;em>Reset Delay&lt;/em>-button is used to reset the delay to zero. Pressing the &lt;em>Take transition&lt;/em>-button causes the simulated system to fire the selected transition at the specified time. The &lt;em>Reset&lt;/em>-button is used to reset the simulated system to its initial state.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Variables Panel</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/variables/</guid><description>&lt;p>The variables panel is the middle panel of the simulator. It displays the values of the data and clock variables in the current state or transition selected in the trace of the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control&lt;/a> panel.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Process Panel</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/process/</guid><description>&lt;p>The process panel is the rightmost upper panel of the simulator. It displays the process instances of the system descriptions. A red token marks the current control point of each automaton. One or more of the automata edges may also be red to indicate the transition currently selected in the simulation control panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking inside a process box with the right mouse button opens a pop-up menu with the following items:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Message Sequence Chart</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/sequence-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/sequence-chart/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Message Sequence Chart (MSC) panel is the lower rightmost panel of the simulator. It displays an MSC view of the generated trace (also displayed in the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control panel&lt;/a> of the simulator).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the MSC view there is a vertical line for each process, and a horizontal line for each synchronisation point. The process name of each vertical line is indicated in the upper part of the MSC panel. The node names shown on the vertical lines indicate the control location of the automaton. If the mouse is placed over the MSC all control location names at the position are shown. If a position is selected, the &lt;a href="../process/">process panel&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control&lt;/a> panel are updated accordingly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gantt Chart Panel</title><link>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/gantt-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/concrete-simulator/gantt-chart/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Gantt Chart panel is the middle rightmost panel of the simulator. It displays another view of the generated trace according to the Gantt Chart specification given in &lt;a href="/language-reference/system-description/system-definition/">system definition&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the Gantt Chart view, the horizontal axis represents the time span, and in the vertical axis the list of activities (usually some of the system processes) defined in the Gantt chart specification are listed. A vertical line is used to represent the current time (which corresponds to the one displayed in the &lt;em>Simulation Trace&lt;/em>-combo box). Horizontal bars of varying lengths and colors represent when the different expressions in the Gantt chart specification are satisfied according to the current state of the trace.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>