<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Requirements Specification on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/language-reference/requirements-specification/</link><description>Recent content in Requirements Specification on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/language-reference/requirements-specification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Semantics of the Symbolic Queries</title><link>/language-reference/requirements-specification/symb_queries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/requirements-specification/symb_queries/</guid><description>In the following we give a pseudo-formal semantics for the requirement specification language of UPPAAL. We assume the existence of a timed transition system (S, s0, →) as defined in the semantics of UPPAAL. In the following, p and q are state properties for which we define the following temporal properties:
Possibly The property E&amp;lt;&amp;gt; p evaluates to true for a timed transition system if and only if there is a sequence of alternating delay transitions and action transitions s0 → s1 → &amp;hellip; → sn, where s0 is the initial state and sn satisfies p.</description></item><item><title>Semantics of the Statistical Queries</title><link>/language-reference/requirements-specification/smc_queries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/requirements-specification/smc_queries/</guid><description>UPPAAL can estimate the probability of expression values statistically. There are four types of statistical properties: quantitative, qualitative, comparison and probable value estimation.
Simulation &amp;lsquo;simulate&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;[&amp;rsquo; SMCBounds &amp;lsquo;]&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;{&amp;rsquo; List &amp;lsquo;}&amp;rsquo; [ : Expression [ &amp;lsquo;:&amp;rsquo; SATRUNS ]]
SMCBounds ::= BoundType [ ; RUNS ]
BoundType ::= ( | Clock | &amp;lsquo;#&amp;rsquo; ) &amp;lsquo;&amp;lt;=&amp;rsquo; BOUND
The simulation query collects the valuation of the specified list of expressions over the time, cost or action-transitions of the simulated run.</description></item><item><title>CI Estimation</title><link>/language-reference/requirements-specification/ci_estimation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/language-reference/requirements-specification/ci_estimation/</guid><description>Probability estimation query Pr[&amp;hellip;](&amp;lt;&amp;gt; q) yields a confidence interval (CI) for the probability of the state expression q being true with the confidence level of 1-α. For example, it could be [0.45, 0.55] (95% CI), or could be written as 0.5 ± 0.05 (95% CI), where ε=0.05 and α=0.05.
The frequentist interpretation of CI is that there exists a true probability that the state expression q is true and it is included in that confidence interval, but there is a risk α of making an error (the true probability being outside the confidence interval).</description></item></channel></rss>