<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Symbolic Simulator on UPPAAL Documentation</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/</link><description>Recent content in Symbolic Simulator on UPPAAL Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simulation Control</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/simulation-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/simulation-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>The simulation control is the left panel of the simulator. It is used to control the simulation and to select the (symbolic) state or transition to be visualized in the other two panels of the simulator. The control panel is divided in two parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The upper part is used for performing step-by-step simulation. A list view displays the enabled transitions, with the currently selected transition highlighted. Pressing the &lt;em>Next&lt;/em>-button causes the simulated system to take the selected transition. The &lt;em>Reset&lt;/em>-button is used to reset the simulated system to its initial state.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Variables Panel</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/variables/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/variables/</guid><description>&lt;p>The variables panel is the middle panel of the simulator. It displays the values of the data and clock variables in the current state or transition selected in the trace of the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control&lt;/a> panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The data variable values are always shown as integers. The clock values are shown symbolically as a conjunction of clock guards of lower and upper bounds on individual clocks or differences between pairs of clocks (see &lt;a href="/language-reference/expressions/">Expressions&lt;/a> section for more information on clock guards). The possible clock values of the associated state (or transition) are all possible solutions to the conjunction of all clock constraints. The symbols &amp;ldquo;[&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;]&amp;rdquo; are used for closed intervals and &amp;ldquo;(&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;)&amp;rdquo; for open intervals in the usual way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Process Panel</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/process/</guid><description>&lt;p>The process panel is the rightmost upper panel of the simulator. It displays the process instances of the system descriptions. A red token marks the current control point of each automaton. One or more of the automata edges may also be red to indicate the transition currently selected in the simulation control panel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking inside a process box with the right mouse button opens a pop-up menu with the following items:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Message Sequence Chart</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/sequence-charts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/sequence-charts/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Message Sequence Chart (MSC) panel is the lower rightmost panel of the simulator. It displays an MSC view of the generated trace (also displayed in the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control panel&lt;/a> of the simulator).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the MSC view there is a vertical line for each process, and a horizontal line for each synchronisation point. The process name of each vertical line is indicated in the upper part of the MSC panel. The node names shown on the vertical lines indicate the control location of the automaton. If the mouse is placed over the MSC all control location names at the position are shown. If a position is selected, the &lt;a href="../process/">process panel&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="../simulation-control/">simulation control&lt;/a> panel are updated accordingly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Symbolic Traces</title><link>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/symbolic-traces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gui-reference/symbolic-simulator/symbolic-traces/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since clocks range over the non-negative reals, timed automata can have infinitely many states (not to be confused with locations) and infinitely many traces. The simulator cannot visualize all these concrete traces. Instead it shows an infinite set of traces - a so called symbolic trace. Each symbolic state of a symbolic trace is a set of states and their delay successors described by a number of &lt;a href="../variables/">constraints on the clocks&lt;/a>. In a given symbolic state, the active locations and the values of discrete variables are the same for all states.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>